[writing on chalkboard]
Welcome!
Digital Design with Hossein
Hello everyone!
Welcome dear students in the course digital design
In this course we are going to know or learn how a computer system is workin
[showing the inside of a computer workstation]
As you can see here a typical computer system
Any computer system has three (3) main components
I/O devices.
(1) Here I have a hard disk drive which we store all our files and images
(2) We have a memory module.
All the information must be loaded to memory in order to be processed by other components of a computer system
And (3) the main component which is a CPU, central processing unit
Which does the actual operation and execute the statements
There are two other important parts as well.
Power which gives the electrical power to the whole system
And also a motherboard or mainboard
Which interconnects all these components to each other
I already opened the mainboard (motherboard) from the casing
And you can see here closely all the main components (not the I/O and the power units)
The main component as I said is the CPU.
Behind this cooling fan, which cools down the CPU when executing the operations,
The CPU is installed (presented).
[opening the cooling fan to show the CPU behind it]
I opened this cooling fan, behind it there is a chip which is called cpu
[detaching CPU from the motherboard (mainboard)]
This is the CPU
So basically we are going to zoom inside this structure and see how it is designed
And how it is executing the commands or (program) statements
You might ask why we should know the inside of this digital board or the inside of the CPU
Today we can write the programs and upload them to the cloud (machines)
The cloud is running our programs (nowadays)
You might say that there is no need to know how a computer system is working
The reason is if you know how a computer system is working, you can write programs efficiently
You can write programs that run faster
Or take less space (memory)
So that's (one of) the main reasons that we have know how a computer system is working
Also, at the end of the day, all programs are running on a computer system.
Who knows, one day you might want to work for those cloud companies and want to build the computer system for the cloud system
In this course, however, we are not going to discuss how a computer system is actually built from the physical (layer) perspective
If you want to know that (to build your own computer system)
You have to take advanced courses such as Computer Architecture II, or
(taking courses from) Computer or Electrical programs
In those courses, they teach you how to manufacture hardware
However, in this course, we just want to know what is inside,
How the connections (circuits) are made
And the CPU is executing the commands
Thank you everyone for your attention
And looking forward to seeing you all next week on Monday (September 14, 2020 )
Meanwhile, if you have any questions, or concerns about this course, you can simply send me emails
I will try my best to answer right away
And have a great day
Bye